welcome back everyone
and today I'm going to start the 4th season of GTNH
now, this season
this season I'm going to do things slightly different from the previous seasons
like usually I always made a script
and then I heavily edited everything around that script
I played around trying to make a script do
but the thing is that if I start again a season trying to fit it into script
or make a script (think?) what to put in the video or not
I will end up with a 10 minutes video that I could title how I made the 100 stargates in 10 minutes
this time I'm going to improvise a little bit more
also, I was thinking about making more tutorial like
but there are already so many tutorials of GTNH on YouTube
the only thing left is yet another let's play
like every other let's play there is
so, what I decide to do is that I'm going to try to keep it interesting and useful
I'm going to behave a little bit like when I livestream
but I can cut out all of the boring parts
and I can do retakes if something doesn't show up nicely
since I don't have to follow chat
I can be more focused on the game
maybe we do a few livestreams when I will be doing grinding stuff without progress
so I can also answer your questions and better show stuff
that that's probably more like it
it's going to be filled with tips like
the main idea is that I'm going to show how and why I do things
we'll see how it goes
I just started the game as you saw
the quest book
I threw it away
you can set a shortcut in the
you can set a shortcut (here)
I'm going to fill this season with tips
so, first thing
check out the shortcuts
at the beginning probably you only need a few of those
the thing is that when you see me doing weird things
most likely I'm impressing some shortcut
maybe asking the comments
or if I will livestream, on livestream
my best livestreams are used to be a little bit
let's say
not too friendly
because I wanted to gameplay
this time I'm instead doing gameplay without having to follow chat
and I will follow the comments and some livestreams to follow the chat
it was fine
uh, the quest book, that's a new version
they change so many thing
every new GTNH version, they change so many things
so yeah, you didn't even check this version really
I just jumped in like that, recording
should have should have made a test
instead of jumping in like that
this is still a beta
but by the time you're watching this
most likely the new version is already out
okay there are many new book
I was going to say
if you follow the quest book and do those quests
by the time you read all of these and do this quest
it's going to be already night
and this pack has a really harsh night
my tip is that you can
one thing is that you can put the difficulty in peaceful
another tip is that if you keep wandering around
at some point you can find some buildings
most likely a brick house
there is a house made out of brick
if you can find it
it's super useful
I'm going to look for it at some point later
but for the bricks
if you find it super early game
there is a bed in that brick house
and you can just take that bed
and the night will no longer be an issue
I feel like trying to survive the night in this pack
just don't do it
just get a bed to sleep skip the nights
some people don't
right now I'm looking for some sheep
because if I can't find that brick house
I'm going to rush a bed
you can totally get a bed in the first day
I don't know how many times I did it
this time I'm wasting too much time talking
that's just a first day thing
I don't know what to say
so I'm gonna do
you need like 6 flint if I remember correctly
you need like 6 gravel
you use that to make 2 flint and a little bit of wood
to make a crafting table
crafting tables in GTNH are quite expensive
you need logs, not planks, and flint
I just showed you how to make flint
this one this one
you need the soft mallet
is that how you make it, no
gotta be like that, OK
I'm going by memory to see if I can remember how to actually make a bed by memory
but you can totally look it up in NEI
just like to see
that you need two of those
yes, OK
can totally see, I
I mean, I didn't take
I didn't go too slowly
but I usually can get it by 12:00 am in the game
usually takes me like half the
not half
you can do it in half the time
there was still time left
otherwise you can just (put?) play
like I'm just telling you ways that you can deal with the first night in the game
there are many ways
probably there are better tutorials
also found a village I think
let's go to the village
OK, and this village
let's see if it has one useful thing
or he's so useless
new foods
not even grown
from the map, it should be easier
I think this one has smeltery
if it has smeltery, it's good, useful
this one may contain the things
let's see
uh, where is this
is that a smeltery or not
yes, OK
I found a smeltery, good
later on this will be useful
then looking
oh what is the, oh food
is that a new building
I don't recall this building
did they have new buildings to the villages
yeah I guess so
not even know where I could find stuff now
maybe that's the old thing and I don't remember
yeah and then of course, some people
I'm just an average GregTech player
don't take what I do, what I say, or anything too seriously
just trying to enjoy the game
and showcase how to play it
how many cauldrons does this have
oh, thanks
sleep sleep sleep sleep sleep
also if you didn't know
you can't eat the same food like 4 times in a row
then you start having issues
you have to balance your diet
if you can manage to get everything like that
you get some constant buffs
I think it's speed and haste if you get everything up there
if it goes too low
you start getting slowness and other debuffs
that that is totally new
this update of GTNH added quite a new few structures to villages
so I have no clue which one of those could contain some useful stuff now
probably should just cut out
and when I find something interesting
just show all of it now
I want to see this
this one seems
this one should have
his one has the tinker's
uh wait
uh no it's ink and paper
I don't want to do
this one this one has the (correct?) stuff, OK OK
let's see if I got any useful parts for the early game pickaxes
oh, as you notice
I'm not doing anything in the quest book
my tip is before starting the quest book
you should first of all, rush a bed
the main thing is Day 0, get a bed
that's my take
if you don't want to put peaceful
if you can't get the bed before the first night
just start over a new game
restart the game if you can't get a bed in day 1
that's my take
unless you want to put peaceful or anything else
can I make a pickaxe
oh wait, I found this
I could really make a pickaxe there
so, with this, I can make
I'm going to have to craft it anyways later
for the quest book probably
I'm thinking now
why do I even want a pickaxe
I don't really need it
but good to have
let's get this one I guess
and there I have a pickaxe before even starting the quest book
good
then I can take this one with me so I can repair it
this is basically useless
oh there is a (axe head?)
I can make an axe too maybe
yeah, OK, later
maybe later
the other thing I wanted to say
those obsidian parts are really really good
later on this stuff could be quite handy to do some tier skips
Obsidian parts can be good for tier skipping
we will talk about it in a few episodes
I have no idea how this series is going to turn out
I think I want to start the quests in the actual first episode
this one was like a prequel or something
by the way, you can find those gardens everywhere
if you didn't know
you can pick those up with right click
and if you pick it up
you can later on plant it
and it will slowly spread
so you can plant those and have those grow
or you can just destroy it with left click to get (wood?)
uh was saying
like one year ago
it used to be that, to make water
years ago, you needed this tank to make water
this one worked depending on humidity
and if you had like 20% humidity
this thing will produce one fifth of the optimal water
you can see the humidity
here it's 20%
here is 90%
so it used to be that if I made my house
my factory here
I would get one fifth of the water
that I would get if I made it there
in this game version
we got other ways of getting water early
that was only early game
later on you have better ways
but that used to be the early game
I think in this version it's no longer an issue
in my last speedrun
we actually made our base in a biome that had no rain
you can see desert
this biome has no precipitation
now this one has zero humidity
so I think I if you make a water tank in a desert
I think it doesn't even make water
I may be making this up
I don't know
I would have to test it
but anyways, the point is that if I build where there are no precipitations
there will be no rain
the issue is that rain
if you have an electric machine and it rains on it
the machine will blow up
maybe building your house in a no precipitation biome could be an idea
but you have to be careful
you can see two hours to the next storm
so if I made my house here
and I had an electric machine here
and by mistake I had one missing block on top
and it rained over a machine there
it will blow up
just in case
protect your machines
another funny thing which I don't know if they changed it
it used to be that if you place an electric machine under a river
it will not blow up
so you could put a bucket of water above machines to protect machines from rain
I think they fix it
but I'm not sure
I'm going to build a builder roof anyways
I think most likely I'm going to settle in a biome I like
and this is one of my favorite biomes
the cherry blossom
I think I want to set my base somewhere in this biome
now, do I build it
I was going to say
do I build it on stream or off stream
when it's going to be off stream anyways
it's going to be either recorded or not
most likely we'll also do a few livestreams
I still have to figure things out
also I don't have too much time those days
I'm starting slowly and trying to figure out how I want to do this season
there are probably many many things I'm forgetting
I was looking for a nice flat area for my new base
I think I got it
but what I found is the brick house I was talking about at the beginning of this stream
you can either keep rolling new worlds until you find one before the first night
otherwise, it's rather easy to find and it's super useful
those bricks are extremely valuable
later on in the playthrough or some point you will see
those being quite needed
now give me a moment
here you can find a bed
so you can sleep
and then I'm going to start actually doing thing in the next episode
I think that's more or less it for this episode
I want to start actually doing something with the next video
this looks like a nice area for my new base
by the way, down there there is a dungeon with a really good loot
which I may explore in next episode I don't know
we'll see how I want to go with this
this was just a rush debug basically
and seeing how to configure everything
but the main thing is that I was planning on doing this from few months
I also wanted to explain how to install the game
how to search chunkloading, homes
talk about you can play however you want
maybe some people want to keep inventory
which I kind of suggest
if you're not doing some kind of challenge
or hardcore player or whatever whatever
keeping inventory is really nice to have
this one is a thing to reduce lag
so I wanted to talk about this stuff
but then I figured out I'm not good at explaining things
and there is a dude who made a tutorial which is a really really nice
I'm going to link him in the description
actually I didn't even fully watch his video
but he covered everything I wanted to do and even better
this goes away
then I wanted to talk a little bit about priorities OK
priorities
this is something I'm going to keep mentioning
maybe hopefully in the future
I wanted to explain how I decide what to do, when to do
having priorities figured out is mostly if you want to speedrun
but I'm going to mention it a few times
like if you are waiting
it's not like you are playing the game wrong
but I keep saying
if you find yourself idling in GTNH, you are playing the game wrong
it's not true, but
there are many things you can do in GTNH
eventually we will talk about this
and that's what's more important actually
that's the thing
before priorities have fun
it's a game
remember to have fun
you're playing this
I mean I think you're playing this for fun
let's assume you for fun
I mean one can do a speedrun
I mean even if you do a speedrun
you do it for fun at the end of the day
yeah, I wanted to tell you
there are many things that not even I know
so most of the time
instead of looking around for a solution or an answer
I just want to tell you try and see yourself what happens
like make a test world
make an error where you can try to do something
and try to guess what's the do
make a backup make a backup
do whatever you want
if something happens load a backup
like sometimes it's more fun to
or at least that's OK
that's probably the issue
that's probably that's my opinion
other people may like more to go around
and read somewhere what happens if you do something
I'm more kind of the person who rather makes a backup
blows something up to see what happens
and then loads a backup
you can test things in the game
and that's about finding your own way of playing
figure out how you like to play the game
also, you don't have to play this game
sometime I'm going through this because some people
I had comments asking me
how can you enjoy this game
oh, look at how boring this game is
don't you get tired of building factories
why do you always do long
and all of those comments
and I get tired
I mean, can I play however I like
if you don't like this game
you don't have to play this game
if you don't like it
don't play it
I'm going to show you how I play
many people ask
I was also wonder how I'm so fast out
I I don't think I'm that good
there are people who are better than me at this game
but I'm going to show you in this season mostly "why"
I'm going to try to emphasize why I do things in a specific way
I'm not doing a speedrun tutorial
but I'm going to try to explain you my decisions
then again, oftentimes I do things that are not optimal
because I like more than an optimal way than the optimal one
also I'm quite lazy
so there is that too
I will never remember everything that I have to place inside a video
I know that there are things that
someone is going to come up with questions I couldn't have figured out before someone asks anyways
I can only put only so much stuff in the videos
I don't even remember what this is supposed to mean
there are different play styles I think that was inside this one
so now I can delete this file
so that was like a prequel for this season
hopefully it won't be too boring or I don't know
yeahI don't even know what I'm doing in my life
we see how this goes, OK
see you with the first episode
because I'm going to call this episode 0
bye bye
欢迎大家回来
今天我要开始GTNH的第四季
现在，这一季
这一季我会做些和之前几季不太一样的事
比如以前我总是会先写个脚本
然后围绕那个脚本大幅度地编辑内容
我会反复调整，努力让脚本起作用
但问题是，如果我重新开始一季还试图套进脚本里
或者写个脚本去琢磨视频里该放什么不该放什么
最后做出来的就会是一个10分钟的视频，标题可以叫《我是如何在10分钟里造100个星门的》
这次我会更多地进行即兴发挥
另外，我也考虑过做成更像教程的形式
但YouTube上已经有太多GTNH的教程了
唯一还缺的，不过是又一个实况系列
就像其他那些实况系列一样
所以我决定，我会努力让它既有意思又有用
我会表现得有点像直播时的状态
但我可以把所有无聊的部分都剪掉
如果有什么东西没展示好，我也可以重录
既然不需要实时看聊天
我可以更专注于游戏本身
也许我会在刷枯燥的东西、没什么进展的时候做几次直播
这样我也可以回答你们的问题，更好地展示内容
这样大概才对
这一季会充满各种小技巧
主要想法是，我会展示我做事的方式和原因
看看效果如何
就像你看到的，我刚进入游戏
任务书
我把它扔了
你可以在这里设置快捷键
可以在这里设置快捷键
这一季我会塞满各种小技巧
所以，第一件事
看看这些快捷键
刚开始你可能只需要其中的几个
问题是，当你看到我做奇怪的事情时
多半是我在演示某个快捷键
可以问问评论区
或者如果我搞直播的话，在直播里问
我最好的直播，过去都有点
怎么说呢
不太友好
因为我想专注于游戏本身
这次我不需要关注聊天，专注于游戏
我会看评论区，也会通过一些直播来聊天
这样挺好的
呃，任务书，这是新版本的
他们改了太多东西
每个新GTNH版本，他们都会改很多东西
所以是啊，我其实都没好好看过这个版本
我就这么直接跳进来开始录了
本应该先做个测试的
而不是这样直接跳进来
这还是测试版
但当你们看到这个视频的时候
新版本很可能已经出来了
好吧，有很多新书
我正想说
如果你跟着任务书做那些任务
等你看完所有这些任务说明、做完任务
天早就黑了
而这个整合包的夜晚非常危险
我的建议是你可以
一个办法是把难度调成和平
另一个建议是，如果你一直四处逛
最终能找到一些建筑
很可能是砖房
有一座砖砌的房子
如果你能找到它
会非常有用
我打算之后找个时间去找找
但说到砖块
如果你在游戏极早期就找到它
那个砖房里有一张床
你可以直接把那张床拿走
夜晚就不再是问题了
在这个整合包里试图熬过夜晚
还是别这么干了
直接找张床睡觉，跳过夜晚吧
有些人就不这么做
现在我正在找羊
因为如果我找不到那个砖房
我就赶紧合成床
你完全可以在第一天就搞到床
我也不知道自己干过多少次了
这次我花太多时间说话了
那只是第一天的事而已
我不知道该说什么
所以我就直接做了
如果我没记错的话，你需要大概6个燧石
你需要大概6个砾石
用它们做出2个燧石和一点木头
来做一个工作台
GTNH里的工作台相当昂贵
你需要原木，不是木板，还有燧石
我刚才刚给你展示了怎么做燧石
这个，这个
你需要软锤
是这样做的吗？不对
得这样才行
我在凭记忆回想，看自己能不能记得做床的方法
但你完全可以在NEI里查
就是想看看
你需要两个这个
好了
完全可以看到，我
我是说，我没
我没走太慢
但我通常能在游戏时间中午12点之前搞定
大概只需要我一半的
不是一半
只需要一半的时间就能搞定
时间还有剩
不然你也可以直接放水
我只是在告诉你应对游戏第一晚的各种方法
有很多方法
可能还有更好的教程
我觉得我好像还找到了一个村庄
我们去村庄看看
好的，这个村庄
看看有没有什么有用的东西
噢它一点用都没有
新的食物
还没长好
从地图上看应该更容易找
我觉得这个有冶炼炉
如果有冶炼炉，那就好了，很有用
这个里面可能有东西
来看看
呃，这是哪儿
那是不是冶炼炉
是的，没错
我找到了一个冶炼炉，很好
之后这会有用的
看看
哦，这是什么，哦，食物
那是新建筑吗
我不记得有这栋建筑
村庄里加了新建筑吗
好像是吧
现在我都不知道上哪儿找东西了
也许那是旧的东西，我不记得了
是啊，而且当然了，有些人
我只是个普通的GregTech玩家
别把我做的事、说的话或任何东西太当真
只是想享受游戏
并展示怎么玩
这个里面有几个炼药锅
哦，谢谢
睡觉睡觉睡觉睡觉睡觉
另外，如果你不知道的话
你不能连续吃同样的食物四次
否则你的身体会出问题
你得平衡你的饮食
如果你能做到每种食物都吃
你会获得一些常驻的增益效果
我觉得如果你各项都吃到满，会获得速度和急迫效果
如果数值太低
你会开始获得缓慢和其他减益效果
那完全是新的
这次GTNH的更新给村庄加了不少新建筑
所以我现在完全不知道哪些建筑里可能有有用的东西
可能应该直接剪掉
等我找到有意思的东西的时候
再全部展示出来
我想看看这个
这个看起来
这个应该有
这个有工匠的
呃等等
哦不，是墨水和纸
我不想做
这个这个里有好东西，好好好
看看我有没有什么前期做镐的有用部件
哦，你可以注意到
任务书我碰都没碰
我的建议是，在开始做任务书之前
你应该先赶紧弄到一张床
最重要的是第0天，先搞到床
这是我的看法
如果你不想调成和平模式
如果你在第一晚之前搞不到床
那就直接重开一个新档
如果你在第一天搞不到床，就重开
这是我的看法
除非你想调成和平模式或者其他什么的
我能做把镐吗
哦等等，我找到了这个
我真的可以做一把镐
所以，有了这个，我可以做
反正之后我也得做的
估计是为了任务书
我在想
我到底为什么要做镐
其实我不怎么需要
但有总比没有好
就拿这个吧
在开始做任务书之前我就能拿到一把镐了
好
然后这个我可以带走，这样就能修复它
这个基本上没用
哦，这里有个斧刃
也许我也能做把斧头
嗯，好的，等会儿
也许以后再说
另一件我想说的是
那些黑曜石部件真的非常好
以后这些东西可以用来跳阶段
黑曜石部件可以用来跳阶段
我们过几集再聊这个
我不知道这个系列会做成什么样
我想在第一集里正式开始做任务
这一集算是前传之类的东西
顺便说一下，那些花园到处都是
如果你不知道的话
你可以右键把它们收起来
如果你收起来
以后可以再种下去
然后它会慢慢传播
所以你可以种下它们让它们生长
或者你可以直接左键打掉来获得木头
呃，刚才说到
大概一年前
以前是这样的，要获得水
几年前，你需要这个水箱来获得水
这个是根据湿度来工作的
如果你只有20%的湿度
这个东西产水只有最优情况的五分之一
你可以看到湿度
这里是20%
这里是90%
所以过去如果我把家建在这里
我的工厂建在这里
我获得的水量
就只有建在那里的五分之一
在这个游戏版本里
我们有了其他早期获得水的办法
那只是前期而已
后期你有更好的方法
但以前这确实是前期的办法
我觉得在这个版本里这已经不是问题了
在我的上一个速通中
我们实际上把基地建在了一个不下雨的生物群系里
你可以看到沙漠
这个生物群系没有降水
现在这个湿度为零
所以我想如果你在沙漠里建水箱
我猜它甚至都不产水
这可能是我瞎编的
我不知道
我得测试一下才知道
但不管怎样，重点是如果我把基地建在没有降水的地方
就不会有雨
问题是雨
如果你有一台电力机器，雨淋到它上面
机器会爆炸
也许把你的家建在没有降水的生物群系里是个好主意
但你得小心
你可以看到距离下次降雨还有两小时
所以如果我把家建在这里
而这里有一台电力机器
要是我少放了一个方块在顶上
雨淋到了那里的机器
它就会爆炸
以防万一
保护好你的机器
另一个有趣的事，我不知道他们改了没有
以前如果你把电力机器放在水流下面
它是不会爆炸的
所以你可以在机器上面放一桶水来保护机器不被雨淋
我觉得他们修复了
但我不确定
不过反正我会建个屋顶
我觉得我很可能会定居在我喜欢的生物群系里
这是我最喜欢的生物群系之一
樱花林
我想在这个生物群系的某个地方建基地
现在，我是在直播时建它
我正想说
我是在直播时建还是不在直播时建
反正不在直播的时候
要么录下来，要么不录
很可能我们也会做几次直播
但我还得先想清楚
而且我这阵子也没太多时间
我会慢慢开始，想想这一季我想怎么做
可能有很多很多事情我忘了
我在给我的新基地找一块好平地
我想我找到了
但我找到的是我在这一集开头提到的那栋砖房
你可以一直刷新新世界，直到在第一晚之前找到一个
否则，它也挺好找的，而且非常有用
那些砖块非常珍贵
在之后的游玩过程中，某个时候你就会发现
那些砖块挺缺的
给我一点时间
在这里你可以找到一张床
这样你就能睡觉了
然后我会在下一集正式开始做事
我觉得这一集差不多就这样了
我想在下一个视频里真正开始做些事
这个地方看起来很适合建新基地
顺便说一句，那边下面有个地牢，战利品很不错
我可能会在下一集探索一下，还不知道
到时候看我想怎么安排
这基本上就是一次快速测试
看看怎么配置各种东西
但主要是，这件事我已经计划了几个月了
我本来也想解释一下怎么安装游戏
怎么搜索区块加载、家的传送点这些东西
聊聊你可以按照自己喜欢的方式玩
也许有些人想保留物品栏
我其实挺建议这么做的
如果你不是在做什么挑战
或者不是硬核玩家什么的
保留物品栏真的很不错
这个设置是用来减少卡顿的
所以我想聊聊这些东西
但后来我发现我不擅长解释
而有个家伙做了一个教程，真的非常好
我会把他的链接放在简介里
其实我也没有完整看完他的视频
但他把我所有想讲的都讲了，而且讲得更好
这个去掉了
然后我想稍微聊聊优先级，好吧
优先级
这是我之后会反复提到的东西
也许希望将来能
我想解释我如何决定做什么、什么时候做
搞清楚优先级主要是如果你想要速通的话
但我会提几次
比如如果你在干等着
不是说你就玩错了
但我一直在说
如果你在GTNH里闲得没事干，那你就玩错了
这话不完全对，但是
GTNH里有很多事可以做
我们之后会聊到这个
其实这才是更重要的
就是这样
在优先级之前，先要有乐趣
这是个游戏
记得要玩得开心
你在玩这个
我觉得你玩这个是为了开心
我们就假设你是为了开心
我是说，你可以做速通
但即使你做了速通
归根结底你也是为了开心
是啊，我想告诉你们
有很多事连我都不知道
所以大多数时候
与其到处找解决方案或答案
我更想告诉你，自己去试试看会发生什么
比如做一个测试世界
故意犯个错，试试看会怎样
然后猜猜该怎么办
先备份先备份
你想怎么做都行
如果出问题了，就加载备份
有时候这样更有趣
或者至少也没关系
那可能就是问题所在
那只是我的看法
其他人可能更喜欢四处看看
然后去查查做某件事会发生什么
我属于那种宁愿先备份的人
炸掉点东西看看会发生什么
然后再加载备份
你可以在游戏里测试
这就是找到你自己的游戏方式
弄清楚你喜欢怎么玩这个游戏
而且，你不一定要玩这个游戏
有时候我提这个是因为有些人
有评论问我
你怎么能享受这个游戏
哦，看这游戏多无聊
你建工厂不腻吗
你为什么总是做那么长时间
诸如此类的评论
我也会累
我是说，我不能按自己喜欢的方式玩吗
如果你不喜欢这个游戏
你不一定要玩这个游戏
如果你不喜欢
就别玩
我会向你展示我是怎么玩的
很多人问
我也想知道我怎么这么快就出去了
我觉得我没那么厉害
这个游戏里有人比我强
但这一季我主要想展示的是"为什么"
我会试着强调为什么我用特定的方式做事
我不是在做速通教程
但我会试着解释我的决策
再说，我经常做一些并非最优的事情
因为我喜欢的不是最优的方式，而是我更喜欢的方式
而且我也挺懒的
所以也有这个原因
我永远不会记得视频里要放的所有内容
我知道有些事情
总会有人提出我事先想不到的问题，反正总会有人问的
我只能往视频里塞这么多东西
我都不记得这应该是什么意思了
有不同的玩法，我觉得这是其中之一
所以现在我可以删掉这个文件了
这就像是这一季的前传
希望不会太无聊，我也不知道
是啊，我甚至不知道自己在干什么
我们看看效果如何
第一集见
因为我要把这一集叫做第0集
拜拜